spamhaus.org 2018-07-17

# Privacy Policy - The Spamhaus Project

Legal  
Copyright  
Trademarks  
Document Storage Policy  
| We at Spamhaus are committed to respecting your online privacy and recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") you share with us.

Spamhaus has established this Online Privacy Policy so that you can understand the care with which we intend to treat your Personal Information.

Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, a home or other physical address and an email address or other contact information, whether at work or at home. In general, you can visit Spamhaus's Web pages without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information about yourself.

If you choose to provide us with your Personal Information on the Web, we may transfer that Information within Spamhaus or to Spamhaus's third-party service providers, across borders, and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world.

Spamhaus strives to comply with all applicable laws around the globe that are designed to protect your privacy. Although legal requirements may vary from country to country, Spamhaus intends to adhere to the principles set forth in this Online Privacy Policy even if, in connection with the above, we transfer your Personal Information from your country to countries that may not require an "adequate" level of protection for your Personal Information. In other words, our goal is to provide protection for your Personal Information no matter where that Personal Information is collected, transferred, or retained.

**Marketing**

Spamhaus does not do any type of marketing. Information collected on Spamhaus's site will not be used for any marketing purpose and will not be sold or otherwise disclosed to any third party for marketing purposes.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

Parts of the Spamhaus website use cookies to control access to pages and database records. Where used, these cookies are for our site security purposes only. If you decline to accept a cookie from the Spamhaus site, the site may decline to grant you access to pages.

Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; and dates and times that our site is accessed.

| **Choice**

You may choose whether or not to provide Personal Information to Spamhaus. The notice we intend to provide where Spamhaus collects Personal Information on the Web should help you to make this choice. If you choose not to provide the Personal Information we request, you can still visit most of Spamhaus's Web sites, but you may be unable to access certain features, options, and services that involve our interaction with you.

**Security**

Wherever your Personal Information may be held within Spamhaus or on its behalf, we intend to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the Personal Information that you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure.

**Third Party Services**

Third parties provide certain services on Spamhaus's behalf. Spamhaus may provide information, including Personal Information, that Spamhaus collects on the Web to third-party service providers to help us deliver programs, products, information, and services. Spamhaus will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third-party service providers are obligated to protect Personal Information on Spamhaus's behalf.

Spamhaus does not intend to transfer Personal Information without your consent to third parties who are not bound to act on Spamhaus's behalf unless such transfer is legally required. Similarly, it is against Spamhaus's policy to sell Personal Information collected online.

**Your Consent**

By using this Web site, you consent to the terms of our Online Privacy Policy and to Spamhaus's processing of Personal Information for the purposes given above as well as those explained where Spamhaus collects Personal Information on the Web. Should the Online Privacy Policy change, we intend to take every reasonable step to ensure that these changes are brought to your attention by posting all changes prominently on our web site for a reasonable period of time.

v.1.0  
1 January 2007
